<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writeups on MR</title><link>https://mreider.com/writeups/</link><description>Recent content in Writeups on MR</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mreider.com/writeups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leonard and Hungry Paul</title><link>https://mreider.com/writeups/leonard-and-hungry-paul/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/writeups/leonard-and-hungry-paul/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.audible.com/pd/Leonard-and-Hungry-Paul-Audiobook/"&gt;Leonard and Hungry Paul&lt;/a&gt; by Ronan Hession is a fun, dry, wholesome, and satisfyiing story about some normal people just sort of going through life together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in the story we meet Leonard and Hungry Paul, two simple and straightforward men who schedule regular gaming nights to play things like Yahtzee, Monopoly, Connect Four, or checkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storyline is about transition. Hungry Paul&amp;rsquo;s sister is getting married, which symbolizes her separation from her parents (whom Paul lives with), from Paul himself, and signals a new phase of all of their lives. There is also Leonard, who experiences both loss and new beginnings and tries to figure out what his life looks like.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Good Whale</title><link>https://mreider.com/writeups/the-good-whale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/writeups/the-good-whale/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/podcasts/serial-good-whale.html"&gt;The Good Whale&lt;/a&gt; is an engaging and emotional Serial podcast series about the 10+ year effort to reintroduce Keiko, the killer whale that starred in Free Willy, into the open ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each episode of The Good Whale reminded me of This American Life (no coincidence, as Ira Glass is one of the producers) in how it tells a story by interviewing the people involved and reflecting on their conflicting views to show that there isn&amp;rsquo;t one way of looking at the story. It also places some suspicion on people&amp;rsquo;s motives and leaves you wondering about people&amp;rsquo;s intentions and truthfulness (some likely not even conscious to them) along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>