<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech / Product writing on MR</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech / Product writing on MR</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mreider.com/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why AI won't take control</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/ai-hype/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/ai-hype/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI went from a niche tech topic to a mainstream obsession in just the last 24 months. Unlike other hyped technologies that promised future revolutions, AI delivers immediate value anyone can experience. People can jump onto ChatGPT and be dazzled by its ability to write a poem, draft an email, or provide information that previously required a Google search. This immediate, almost magical utility has transformed AI from industry jargon into a household term.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>More Zelinskiy</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/more-zelinskiy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/more-zelinskiy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;More Zelenskiy! He wasn’t rude or disrespectful. He just asked a simple question: If we need diplomacy to counter Russian aggression, what kind of diplomacy is that? Should he be ushered from the White House for a reasonable question? Is this pure defiance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, yes. It actually is. And we need more of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defiance is what leaders do! They speak their minds. They stay true to their beliefs. They don&amp;rsquo;t kiss people&amp;rsquo;s asses just because their powerful or rich.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>LinkedIn, Geopolitics, and Silence</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/linked-in-refuge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/linked-in-refuge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Note: I nolonger believe that LinkedIn should be a refuge from political news, as I said in the post the &lt;a href="more_zelinskiy.md"&gt;following week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My office in the Dynatrace Vienna Tower shares space with various companies and organizations, including the embassies of Norway, Australia, and New Zealand. Today, these three embassies organized a brief moment of silence outside our building to honor those who have suffered and lost their lives as a result of the Russian war of aggression in Ukraine. I took the elevator downstairs, stepped outside, and joined everyone in that quiet reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Email Subscriptions from Static Blogs</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/email-subscriptions-from-static-blogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/email-subscriptions-from-static-blogs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="krems_static_site_generator.md"&gt;last blog entry&lt;/a&gt;, I introduced Krems, a project I built for generating static blogs. One of the challenges with static blogs is their inability to run server-side code or databases, which makes storing email addresses for blog subscriptions impossible. To work around this, you can either use a paid service like &lt;a href="https://rssfeedpulse.com"&gt;rssfeedpulse.com&lt;/a&gt; to scrape your RSS feed and email new posts to subscribers, or you can encourage readers to follow your blog using an RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Krems static blog generator</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/krems-static-site-generator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/krems-static-site-generator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago we visited a little town named Krems about an hour West of Vienna. In that little town is a University where my son would apply, though now that he’s been accepted to a few schools in Scotland he likely won’t attend. After we returned to Vienna I thought about writing a short blog about our visit there, but to my horror my blog was nolonger loading properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sudowrite, ChatGPT, and AI Slop</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/sudowrite-chatgpt-and-ai-slop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/sudowrite-chatgpt-and-ai-slop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Like a million other people, I’m trying to write a novel—a character-driven thriller. We’ll see how far I get. Admittedly, I use ChatGPT here and there, but I try to use it lightly. it’s a time-saver for small changes and touch-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, ChatGPT is too general-purpose for writers and often resorts to “corporate-speak,” even after you scold it. This led me to try &lt;a href="https://sudowrite.com"&gt;Sudowrite&lt;/a&gt;, which is built on language models like GPT but devoted to and designed for aspiring authors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Strategy Starts with Sacrifice</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/trade-off-as-strategy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/trade-off-as-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Before I get started, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain why I’m blogging. I began offering pro-bono product advice, hoping to charge a fee someday. While I had some success, balancing a full-time job, family, and personal interests didn&amp;rsquo;t work out well. What did work out was writing about other people’s challenges. I like it. And, it&amp;rsquo;s freeing since the problems aren’t tied to my workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about the importance of sacrifice in product strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bluesky is almost like 2012 Twitter</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/blue-sky/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/blue-sky/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bluesky is going ok so far. I don’t have many followers yet, and I’m still figuring out who to follow, but it’s the closest thing we’ve had in years to 2012 Twitter—the good Twitter. The one where tech folks could have fun, feel connected, and not drown in nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then we wondered how Twitter would make money. Bluesky is in the same place. But unlike Twitter, which grew organically from a quirky SMS tool, Bluesky isn’t organic. It has a clearer sense of what it wants to be—or maybe it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Certainty, Ambivalence, and Product Leadership</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/on-ambivalence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/on-ambivalence/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every night at 9:00 PM, I walk my dog, Leo, while listening to podcasts. Lately, I’ve been into &lt;strong&gt;Hidden Brain&lt;/strong&gt; with Shankar Vedantam. In a &lt;a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/the-benefits-of-mixed-emotions/"&gt;recent episode&lt;/a&gt;, Naomi Rothman talked about how society values leaders who project certainty over ambivalence—often favoring confidence even when it’s based on incomplete or inaccurate information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rothman cited a study where CEOs who admitted uncertainty during earnings calls were judged more harshly and seen as less competent, even though they were being honest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doing It for Yourself</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/doing-it-for-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/doing-it-for-yourself/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This might sound a bit like “get off my lawn” grumbling, but it’s been on my mind lately. I recently had a conversation with a product manager from another company that left me thinking. Every time he referred to an initiative, he called it “mine,” as if shouting, “Me!” Deadlines and priorities were framed as “important for me”—not for the team, not for the users, but for himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one level, this is human nature. We all bring some degree of self-interest to the work we do. But when a product manager frames everything this way, it stops feeling like a team effort and starts looking like a personal project tied to their ego.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware, Pivotal, and the Rise of Kubernetes</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/pivotal-and-the-rise-of-cloud-foundry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/pivotal-and-the-rise-of-cloud-foundry/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I left Engine Yard (&lt;a href="https://mreider.com/tech/Tales_from_Engineyard.html"&gt;see my earlier post&lt;/a&gt;), I joined VMware to work on the Cloud Foundry team. The idea was ambitious: create a PaaS (Platform as a Service) that allowed developers to write and deploy applications without worrying about infrastructure. It wasn’t revolutionary—Heroku and Engine Yard had similar goals—but it offered something enterprises hadn’t seen before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret weapon was BOSH, a powerful orchestration tool that deployed Cloud Foundry on private or public clouds in a declarative, repeatable way. BOSH had a small but passionate following, with its precision and reliability appealing to those managing complex software deployments. Still, Cloud Foundry itself struggled to balance the needs of developers with the expectations of enterprises. For VMware, it was a critical play to stay relevant as Amazon reshaped the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Quacker: A Weekend Project with ChatGPT</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/building-quacker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/building-quacker/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I built &lt;a href="https://github.com/mreider/quacker"&gt;Quacker&lt;/a&gt;, a Python app that lets static blogs send newsletters. Static blogs are great—simple, fast, and reliable—but they don’t have built-in features like email subscriptions or post notifications. I could’ve used something like Ghost, but instead, I spent the weekend reinventing the wheel. Maybe not the smartest choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quacker does what I need: it adds a subscription form to my blog, stores emails, checks the RSS feed for updates, and sends subscribers an email when there’s a new post. It’s not fancy, and there are better tools out there, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Founders Don’t Need a Strategist as the First PM</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/henchman-or-hero/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/henchman-or-hero/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spoke with the CEO of a small, scrappy, and profitable startup. Let’s call him Mike. His company pulls in a few million dollars a year with a lean team. They’ve made it past the survival stage, but now they’re grappling with the next big question: how to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike’s team is stuck on a familiar startup dilemma: which user to prioritize. Mike wants to focus on buyers, adding features like loyalty programs, promotions, and customer acquisition tools. His team, on the other hand, is more focused on the practitioners. Helping them means pushing to reduce pain points, automate workflows, and fix bugs. Classic short-term vs. long-term thinking, but also a split in who the team believes matters most.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Engine Yard and the Cost of Venture Capital</title><link>https://mreider.com/tech/tales-from-engineyard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/tech/tales-from-engineyard/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the early days of cloud computing, before &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; meant what it does today, we were one of the original cloud vendors. Our infrastructure ran on custom-patched Gentoo servers—nicknamed &amp;ldquo;pizza boxes&amp;rdquo;—housed in two data centers on opposite coasts. Scaling wasn’t automated. It was manual, requiring real humans to intervene. As our head of support jokingly put it, we were a &amp;ldquo;meat cloud.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, we were ahead of the curve, offering a platform as a service (PaaS) for Ruby on Rails apps, MongoDB, and MySQL databases. Developers could push their code, and it “just worked.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>