<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Artists &amp; writers in my family on MR</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/</link><description>Recent content in Artists &amp; writers in my family on MR</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mreider.com/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Charlotte Reider-Smith</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/charlotte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/family/charlotte/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My inspiration comes from the many layers of my life and the people around me. My work is sourced from photographs taken by me and my partner (both film photographers) of our lives together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more information about my work at &lt;a href="https://charlottereidersmith.com"&gt;charlottereidersmith.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/charlotte/char.png" alt="charlotte"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deborah Green</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/deb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/family/deb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Deborah is my Aunt. She lives in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/deb/deb.jpg" alt="deborah"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deb wrote a One Boy about raising her son, Caleb (my cousin), after the passing of her husband and Caleb&amp;rsquo;s father. This is the illustration on the front cover that Caleb created when he was a young boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/deb/oneboy.png" alt="book cover"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what she wrote on the back cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consult about and edit early stages of books, as a developmental editor. I did this for faculty at the University of Washington Medical School, and other books, including Aaron Dixon&amp;rsquo;s account of his experience as a leader with the Black Panther Party, and a book by Jerry Mander of San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Janet Reider</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/janet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/family/janet/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Digital has replaced film. The Hasselblad snoozes on a closet shelf. I am more apt to capture aspects of people — young mothers in rapt conversation while their children argue over a plastic toy, the focused energy of men on a park bench talking politics and dedication of a sunbather on a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more information about my work at &lt;a href="https://janetreider.com"&gt;janetreider.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/janet/janet.png" alt="Janet"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jenny Sampson</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/jenny/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/family/jenny/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My focus is with wet plate collodion (tintypes), traditional black and white photography, and commissioned portraiture. She is a member of the &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/rolls_and_tubes/"&gt;Rolls and Tubes Collective&lt;/a&gt; and acting Board President of the &lt;a href="https://www.ebpco.org/"&gt;East Bay Photo Collective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more information about my work at &lt;a href="https://jennysampson.com"&gt;jennysampson.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/jenny/jenny.jpg" alt="Jenny Sampson"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pete Reider</title><link>https://mreider.com/family/pete/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mreider.com/family/pete/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pete was my Dad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mreider.com/images/dad/dad-and-joyce.png" alt="Pete Reider"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He died on August 13, 2015. Pete&amp;rsquo;s obituary is &lt;a href="../dad/obituary.md"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He self-published a little book called Stepping Stones a few years before his death. Here&amp;rsquo;s what he wrote on the back cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These writings. produced in the last fifteen years, reflect the journey from work as a psychiatrist to retirement. I retired in 2003. I then became a member of the Osher Foundation Lifelong Learning Institute at Brandeis University and the Fromm Institute at the University of San Francisco. I have been trying to expand my ability to play, exploring my role as husband, father and grandparent. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say that humor is everything. but it&amp;rsquo;s scary to think of life without it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>