<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on MR</title>
    <link>https://mreider.com/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on MR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mreider.com/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost and Found</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/lost-and-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/lost-and-found/</guid>
      <description>Don’t you hate it when you do something stupid?&#xA;For my son Max, this happened two weeks ago when he left his gym bag on the 26 Strassbahn. He didn’t realize his mistake until hours later.&#xA;He asked if there was a Lost and Found for Wiener Linien, Vienna’s world-class transportation system. I browsed the web and found out about fundamt.gv.at, an incredible nationwide lost-and-found system. It’s an amazing site. Every single item is meticulously categorized.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H₂Oh No</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/h20no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/h20no/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m writing, again, about water.&#xA;Vienna’s water supply is famously clean. It comes straight from the Alps, requiring no treatment whatsoever. No chlorine, no filtration.&#xA;Yes, I read municipal water reports. Don’t judge.&#xA;Unfortunately, our house isn&amp;rsquo;t connected to the local water system. Instead, we rely on a well. Why? It&amp;rsquo;s a mystery, just one of the &amp;ldquo;charms&amp;rdquo; of our rental. The well water is fine for cooking and brushing teeth, but not for drinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going Viral</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/going-viral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/going-viral/</guid>
      <description>Our summer vacation was a three-part trip. First, we celebrated Marty’s 80th birthday on Long Island. Then we headed to Vermont for Rosie and Zach’s wedding. Finally, we wrapped things up in Portugal with the #friends4life Schwartzberg clan.&#xA;Coronavirus made things tricky. The guest list for Marty’s birthday ended up shorter than planned. Alison, an especially important guest, tested positive and spent the week feeling lousy at the Stony Brook Holiday Inn Express.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than 20 Questions</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/more-than-20-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/more-than-20-questions/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we took an American-style road trip (🚙) through the Czech Republic. Originally, we were considering Holland or Norway, but we procrastinated, and airfares shot up. So, we decided to drive north instead.&#xA;On the Road As with other vacations, this one began by dropping Leo (🐶) at his second home, a beautiful kennel ranch outside of Linz.&#xA;Nice place, right? Leo agrees. He waltzes in there with confidence, like the mayor of Dogville.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Year Went By</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/a-year-went-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/a-year-went-by/</guid>
      <description>I stopped writing over a year ago. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why. Maybe I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling it.&#xA;But today, I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a quick update.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;ve had some new experiences. We went skiing on a couple of glaciers. We got a hyperactive dog named Leo. We visited friends and family in America, then went scuba diving in Costa Rica. In the autumn, we explored Belgium and climbed the Eiffel Tower. Winter came, and we traveled to Florence with my niece, sister, mom, and my mom&amp;rsquo;s husband.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teamwork in Corfu</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/teamwork-in-corfu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/teamwork-in-corfu/</guid>
      <description>I learned some important things during our vacation in Corfu: wasps don’t like smoke, Google Maps can make you drive in circles, and Jacques Cousteau invented scuba diving.&#xA;The scuba diving bit came up on this boat in the town of Nisaki, on Corfu’s northeast side. If you look closely, you’ll see Chris, the owner of Apollo Dive, sitting with my wife and kids.&#xA;Chris and his wife Maria led us on five dives in total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wasser, Acqua, Voda</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/wasser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/wasser/</guid>
      <description>The Danube flows less than a mile from our house. One hot day, I biked there, took off my shirt, and jumped in. The current was strong, pulling me eastward toward Vienna. Thankfully, I made it back home in time for dinner.&#xA;A few weeks later, we drove to a bigger body of water, the Adriatic. Specifically, Venice, home to St. Mark&amp;rsquo;s corpse, Peggy Guggenheim&amp;rsquo;s dog cemetery, tagliatelle, and gondoliers. In Venice, it&amp;rsquo;s legal for a 14-year-old to operate a motorboat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to Kine Fahrrad</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/ode-to-king-fahrrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/ode-to-king-fahrrad/</guid>
      <description>The word “Fahrrad” reminds me of King Fahd of Saudi Arabia. But no, it’s not about that. Ein Fahrrad just means “a bicycle.” And this long-overdue blog post is about my bicycle and what it’s like to use it around town. Whoa. Calm down. You’re too excited.&#xA;Last fall, I bought a used bicycle for €170 from B7 Cycling Center, a shop that hires former inmates and trains them as mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Snowing</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/its-snowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/its-snowing/</guid>
      <description>Snow is falling in Linz today, which makes the kids very happy. I put on some ski gear and rode my bike to work, alongside dozens of other people doing the same.&#xA;The snow fits the scenery perfectly. Linz is fully decked out for Christmas. Lights are strung above the streets: clear lights, globes, stars, and multi-colored spirals.&#xA;Linz boasts three different Christmas markets within a half-mile radius. The market at Main Square has tasty Glühwein.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/infinite-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/infinite-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>We bought Max and Zoe smartphones in June. This was a big deal for us. The plan was to wait until Max started high school. But we caved. An obvious bribe, compensation for the chaos that followed.&#xA;Of course, the phones are incredibly useful, especially for translation and texting. Maps are a lifesaver too. I can see when they&amp;rsquo;re at school, at home, or on a tram.&#xA;The current map looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trader Joe&#39;s Bros</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/trader-joes-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/trader-joes-bros/</guid>
      <description>There are three supermarkets within a five-minute bike ride of our flat: Merkur Markt, Hofer, and Billa.&#xA;Merkur Markt Merkur Markt has the most variety. You can find veggie dogs, sushi rolls, and lots of fresh produce. They even have giant homemade gummy bears, which I’m a big fan of.&#xA;Billa Billa isn&amp;rsquo;t as nice as Merkur, but it does the job. The location near my office sells tuna sandwiches for €2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urfahraner Market</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/urfahraner-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/urfahraner-market/</guid>
      <description>We visited the Urfahraner Market on Saturday. A market it isn&amp;rsquo;t, more like a county fair. We were joined by new friends (thank God Alison is good at making them). Without her, we&amp;rsquo;d be very bored. And thank goodness these befriended friends are fun. Incriminating evidence to follow.&#xA;These friends came with kid-friends too. Fun was had by all: grown-up bunny-ear fun and kid fun on the Autodrom (bumper cars). But this wasn&amp;rsquo;t your ordinary Autodrom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Vermont</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/memories-of-vermont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/memories-of-vermont/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a work trip this week. Four of us are visiting a satellite office in Klagenfurt to meet the team and join some planning sessions. We took a five-hour train ride through the Alps. It was mostly dark and foggy, but whenever the fog lifted, I found myself comparing the countryside to places in America. The mountains look like the Rockies, big peaks and spires, but the grass and trees are a vivid, perfect green, just like Vermont.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Everything Animal</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/everything-animal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/everything-animal/</guid>
      <description>We’re ahead of ourselves. We want it to be April 2020, not September 2019. By April, the kids will take the tram on their own. They’ll have strong friendships. Alison and I will understand the healthcare system and know enough German to order a sandwich without having to point.&#xA;But it’s still September. We have to wait for the sun and moon to come and go 150 times.&#xA;I wish there were a magical way to fast-forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rolling in my Benzo</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/rolling-benzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/rolling-benzo/</guid>
      <description>Lots of rap lyrics mention benzos. Mercedes Benzos. Fancy cars. I just rented my second one from the Hertz in downtown Linz. It was a triple upgrade from a Ford Fiesta, but the rate stayed the same, just €32 a day. That&amp;rsquo;s how we roll. I rolled it all the way home.&#xA;We rent cars for hauling stuff we can&amp;rsquo;t carry and for getting out of town. Driving around Austria is pretty easy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Comprendo</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/no-comprendo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/no-comprendo/</guid>
      <description>I can’t understand a word these people are saying. But I do understand them on other levels.&#xA;They stack wood like it&amp;rsquo;s an art form. I&amp;rsquo;d probably do the same if I had wood to stack. Their toilets have a little shelf so they can examine their poop. I get it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been known to have similar interests. They&amp;rsquo;re highly attuned to mustard, my favorite condiment (and maybe even my favorite food).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/week-2/</guid>
      <description>The basics are finally in place. The kids have beds and bed frames. We do too. Everyone has somewhere to put their clothes. There’s a dining room table now, along with some temporary folding chairs. Zoe has a desk in her room, and we’ve added some bedside tables.&#xA;The bathroom now houses a new washer and dryer, wedged snugly between the sink and the shower. They&amp;rsquo;re supposed to stack, but they don&amp;rsquo;t stack very well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phones</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/phones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/phones/</guid>
      <description>We swapped our SIM cards for new ones from Hofer Telecom. Yes, Hofer is both a grocery store and a cell phone company. The plan costs $10 a month for 15 gigs of data and unlimited calls. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which felt better, firing AT&amp;amp;T or Comcast. For reference, cable internet here is $39 a month for 100 gigabits.&#xA;Now we have these strange (to us) phone numbers that start with +43, the Austrian country code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Österreich</title>
      <link>https://mreider.com/life/osterreich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mreider.com/life/osterreich/</guid>
      <description>Warning: These posts are never proofread. They will have plenty of misspellings and grammatical errors. Verklagen Sie mich (sue me)!&#xA;Tomorrow marks one week since we arrived in Linz, Austria. We’re living in an apartment on Spazenhofstraße, a quiet street along the Postlingberg Tram line. The building has five ground-level apartments, each with two floors, and five balcony apartments on the top level. The balcony apartment above us is occupied by Herig and Inga, who looked down from their balcony and waved as we arrived.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
